this is blender open-source 3D software
这是Blender开源3D软件
that can be used to make animations
可以用来制作动画的
visual effects game assets or
视觉效果游戏资产或
practically anything 3D and best of all
几乎所有3D的东西 最棒的是
it's 100% free and it always will be if
它是100%免费的 如果它永远是免费的
you've never used it before but you want
你以前从未用过它 但你想
to learn it well then you're in the
要学好它 那么你就是在
right place this is a tutorial for
正确的位置这是一个教程
complete beginners I've been using
我一直在使用的完全初学者
blender for 20 years so I'm going to
搅拌机20年了 所以我要
show you how to use all of its core
向您展示如何使用它的所有核心
features and by the end you'll finish
功能 到最后 您将完成
with not only the confidence to start
不仅有信心开始
your own projects but with your very own
你自己的项目 但你自己的项目
dut animation and I know this looks
Dut动画和我知道这看起来
complex but I promise you it's
很复杂 但我向你保证
achievable for a complete beginner and I
对于一个完全的初学者和我来说是可以实现的
say that with confidence because many
这么说很有信心 因为很多人
already have this is actually the fourth
已经有了这其实是第四个
version of this tutorial I made the
本教程的版本 我制作了
first dut tutorial back in 2016 and I've
2016年的第一个DUT教程 我已经
been remaking it every few years to keep
我每隔几年就重新制作一次 以保持
up with blender's development in that
跟上搅拌机在这方面的发展
time millions of people just like
时间数百万人就像
yourself have gone from having never
你自己已经从从来没有
used 3D to successfully making their own
使用3D成功地制作了他们自己的
Donuts one arst even snuck his into a
甜甜圈一号甚至把他的甜甜圈塞进了一个
little film called everything everywhere
一部名为《无所不在》的小电影
all at once very clever so if you're
一下子变得非常聪明 所以如果你
ready to take your first steps in 3D hit
准备好迈出3D Hit的第一步
the Subscribe button and let's begin
订阅按钮 让我们开始
first go to blender.org download or just
首先转到blender.org下载或直接
click the link in the description then
单击描述中的链接 然后
obviously you got to hit the big
很明显 你得打出大牌
download button once downloaded on
下载按钮 下载时间为
Windows double click it and then just go
Windows双击它 然后继续
through the install steps but if you're
通过安装步骤 但如果您
on a Mac just drag it into the
在Mac上 只需将其拖动到
applications folder then just find the
应用程序文件夹 然后只需找到
blender shortcut and open it then once
搅拌机快捷方式 然后打开它一次
it's open open just click anywhere off
它是打开的 只需点击任意位置即可打开
the splash screen to close it and
闪屏关闭它 然后
welcome to the wonderful world of 3D
欢迎来到3D的奇妙世界
first tip do not get overwhelmed if you
第一个小贴士 如果你
go clicking around you might find lots
去点击一下 你可能会发现很多
of buttons and some of them with very
按钮 其中一些带有非常多的
scary names and it can all get very
可怕的名字 这一切都会变得非常
overwhelming very quickly thing you need
压倒性的、非常迅速的你需要的东西
to know is blunder can do a lot of
知道自己犯了错可以做很多事情
things which means it has a lot of tools
这意味着它有很多工具
but you don't need to know every tool in
但是你不需要知道所有的工具
order to do what you want to do if
命令去做你想做的事情 如果
you're familiar with the 8020 rule
你对8020规则很熟悉
there's really only 20% of blender
实际上只有20%的搅拌机
features that you end up using 80% of
您最终使用80%的
the time and that's what I'm planning to
这就是我计划要做的事
teach you in this tutorial Series so
在本系列教程中教您如何
stay with me and you should be fine
和我在一起 你应该会好起来的
we'll start making the donut in the next
我们下一步就开始做甜甜圈了
video in this one we're just going to
在这段视频中 我们只需
look at the interface and I'm going to
看着界面 我要
show you some of the basic navigation so
向您展示一些基本导航 以便
for starters this view this window right
对于初学者来说 请查看此窗口的右侧
here is your 3D viewport and it's where
这是您的3D视窗 它是
you'll spend probably 90% of your time
你可能会花90%的时间
because it is the 3D World so you can
因为这是3D世界 所以你可以
see that we have three objects here
看 我们这里有三个对象
we've got a camera we've got a cube and
我们有一个摄像机 我们有一个立方体
we've got a lamp and when we click on it
我们有一盏灯 当我们点击它时
you can see it's selected because it has
您可以看到它已被选中 因为它具有
the yellow outline so let's delete the
黄色轮廓 所以让我们删除
default cube of course and replace it
当然是默认多维数据集并替换它
with something else so we could do that
做些其他的事 这样我们就可以这么做了
by going up to the add menu up here or
通过转到此处的添加菜单或
by remembering the hot key which is
通过记住热键 它是
shift a so shift a for add so usually
移位SO移位a加法通常如此
the one you're looking for is underneath
你要找的人就在下面
mesh so these are called your Primitives
网格 所以这些被称为你的基本体
and it's what you use to start something
它是你用来启动某件事的工具
when you're looking to uh make an object
当你想要制作一件物品的时候
like if you're going to make a chair you
比如 如果你要做一把椅子 你
might start with a cylinder as the chair
可能从一个圆柱体作为椅子开始
leg and then build out from there but
腿 然后从那里长出来 但是
the one I'm sure you're all very curious
我相信你们都很好奇的那个
you want to click it it's the monkey so
你想点击它 它是猴子 所以
let's just click the monkey why does
让我们点击一下猴子 为什么
blender have a monkey well fun fact
搅拌机有一个猴子井有趣的事实
every 3D software has its own little
每个3D软件都有它自己的小
random complex object because it's
随机复杂对象 因为它是
useful to test things like shaders or
对测试着色器或
complexities of scenes so 3ds Max has
场景的复杂性 因此3ds Max具有
the Utah teapot Houdini has the toy and
犹他州的胡迪尼茶壶有这个玩具和
I think Pig's head uh blenda has the
我觉得猪头呃布伦达有
monkey and it's actually called the
猴子 它实际上被称为
suzan monkey head which you can see in
苏山猴头 你可以在
the top left there named after the
那里的左上角以
rangang from the film Jay and Silent Bob
电影《周与沉默的鲍勃》中的兰格
Strikes Back random piece of trivia so
回击随意的琐事 所以
let's get a better look at it and to
让我们更好地看一看 然后
that we need to orbit which you can do
我们需要绕轨道运行 你可以这样做
by on your mouse there your scroll wheel
通过你的鼠标点击你的滚轮
that is called your middle Mouse button
这就是你的鼠标中键
if you push that in and then drag around
如果你把它推进去 然后拖来拖去
that is now orbiting now for my laptop
它现在正在为我的笔记本电脑运行
users you've just panicked cuz you
你刚刚惊慌失措的用户因为你
realize you don't have a mouse how are
意识到你没有鼠标你好吗
you going to orbit around first of all
你首先要绕地球转一圈
probably good idea to get a Mouse for 3D
买个3D鼠标可能是个好主意
work it will come in handy um but in a
工作上 它会派上用场的 嗯 但在
pinch you can get by without it just by
没有它你也可以过得很好
up here in the top right hand corner
在这里的右上角
this little gray Circle anywhere in the
这个灰色的小圆圈在任何地方
gray section if you just left click drag
灰色部分 如果您只是左键单击拖动
on that that will do the exact same
在这一点上 这将起到完全相同的作用
thing or if you want you can go to edit
如果你想要的东西 你可以去编辑
preferences and then underneath input
首选项 然后在输入下面
there's emulate three button Mouse and
有模拟三键鼠标和
that means that if you hold down alt and
这意味着如果按住Alt和Alt
then left click drag that will do the
然后左键单击拖动即可完成
exact same thing also whilst you are in
同样的事情 当你在里面的时候
user preferences you might want to go to
您可能想要转到的用户首选项
interface face and you've got resolution
人机界面 你就有了解决方案
scale if you're on a 4k monitor you
如果您使用的是4k显示器 请按比例调整
might find that your menus and buttons
可能会发现你的菜单和按钮
are really small and you kind of have to
真的很小 你必须得
like squint in to see it so personally I
我喜欢眯着眼睛看它 所以我个人
like to keep my 4k monitor around about
我想把我的4k显示器留在身边
1.5 but since this is a tutorial I make
1.5但由于这是我制作的一个教程
it nice and big so you can see what I'm
它又大又漂亮 所以你可以看到我是什么
doing okay so that's orbiting around
做得很好 所以它是在轨道上运行的
with the middle Mouse button if we want
如果需要 可以使用鼠标中键
to zoom in we can do that just by
要放大 我们只需通过
scrolling in and out we could also do it
向内和向外滚动 我们也可以这样做
by going up to the magnifying glass tool
通过使用放大镜工具
there and then just left click dragging
然后只需单击鼠标左键拖动
and then moving the uh mouse back and
然后将鼠标向后移动 然后
forth that does the same thing or you
第四 做同样的事情 否则你
could hold down control and then middle
可以按住Ctrl然后按下鼠标中键
Mouse button and that will do a smooth
鼠标按下按钮 就会做得很流畅
Zoom as well okay so one thing you might
缩放也可以 好的 所以你可能会做一件事
notice looking at this is that it's not
注意 看这个 它不是
very pretty right it's just kind of got
非常正确 只是有点像是
this flat Bland gray lighting over
这片平坦的白兰地灰色灯光
everything and that's because this state
一切都是因为这个州
right now is called viewport shading and
现在被称为视区着色和
it's kind of a lightweight optimized way
这是一种轻量级的优化方式
to view the scene just as you're
就像你看到的场景一样
building it but if you want to create a
构建它 但如果您想要创建
final pretty image that's called r ring
最后一幅美丽的图像被称为R环
and you can actually switch into
你实际上可以切换到
rendered mode by going up here into the
渲染模式 从这里进入
top right hand corner you can see we're
右上角您可以看到我们是
currently in the viewport shading mode
当前处于视口明暗处理模式
if we go to across you should see render
如果我们走到对岸 你应该会看到渲染
View mode so if we click that your
查看模式 因此如果我们单击您的
computer might stall for a quick second
计算机可能会短暂停机
whilst it loads it in but you can see
虽然它加载了它 但你可以看到
it's now different we have directional
现在不同了 我们有了方向
light we have shadow cast across the
光 我们的影子投射在
monkey so it's now currently being lit
猴子 所以它现在正在被点燃
by this lamp up here so if I wanted to
在这盏灯下 所以如果我想
uh you know zoom in on that lamp lamp
呃 你知道 把那盏灯放大
there and just kind of like move it
就在那里 就像是移动它
around you can see it's kind of hard to
在你周围你可以看到 很难
focus on like it's always exactly not in
专注于它 就像它总是完全不在
the right View and that's because we are
正确的观点 那是因为我们
centered on our monkey right now we need
以我们的猴子为中心 现在我们需要
to change the focus we need to pan to
要改变我们需要平移到的焦点
something else so we could do that one
做点别的 这样我们就可以做那个了
of two ways one if you're on a laptop
有两种方法 一种是如果你使用笔记本电脑
you could use a little move tool there
你可以在那里使用一个小的移动工具
that will do that or everyone else shift
会这么做的 否则其他人都会转移
middle Mouse click drag that will do the
鼠标中键单击拖动将执行以下操作
same thing so middle Mouse is for
同样 鼠标中键也是如此
orbiting shift middle Mouse is for pan
动态观察Shift鼠标中键用于平移
to change your view to something else
将您的视线更改为其他内容
okay so I want to move my light because
好的 我想移动我的灯 因为
it's uh it's too Moody I want to be able
这个 呃 太喜怒无常了 我想
to see the monkey's face there so to
看到猴子的脸 所以
move an object you could do it one of
移动一个你可以做的事情之一
two ways one you could go over to the
有两种方法 一种是你可以去
left hand corner here and you've got the
在这里的左手角 你会看到
move tool when you click that you can
单击时移动工具 这样您就可以
see that the selected object the lamp
确保选定的对象是灯
has this uh this Gizmo it's called with
这个 呃 这个叫它的小玩意儿
these axes on it and if I just clicked
上面的这些轴 如果我点击
and dragged on any of those arrows there
把任何一支箭拖到那里
you can see I can move it along any of
你可以看到我可以沿着任何一个方向移动
those axes I could also just click on
我也可以点击这些轴
that uh white circle there and that will
那个 呃 那里的白色圆圈 那会
just freehand drag it um depending on my
只需徒手拖动它 嗯 取决于我的
view but it's kind of tedious every time
但每次都有些单调乏味
you want to move something you have to
你想移动你必须移动的东西
like go to that tool and then find the
比如转到该工具 然后找到
arrows and yada yada so actually most
箭呀 所以其实最多的
people in blender prefer to use the hot
搅拌机里的人更喜欢用热的
keys so we just keep it in the default
密钥 因此我们只需将其保留为默认设置
selection State here and instead
此处和相反的选择状态
remember the hot key which is G for grab
记住热键是G 代表Grab
now I've just tapped the key and you'll
现在我只需轻敲一下键 你就可以
notice as I move my cursor that it's now
请注意 当我移动光标时 它现在是
attached to my cursor it's not my cursor
连接到我的光标 它不是我的光标
isn't even actually close to it in fact
实际上甚至还没有接近它
my cursor could be on the other side of
我的光标可能在另一边
the screen and I could tap G and it will
屏幕和我可以点击G 它就会
move it and at first this is kind of
移动它 一开始这是一种
awkward you're like why is it working
令人尴尬的是 你在想 为什么它起作用了
this way but once you get used to it you
这样 但一旦你习惯了 你就会
realize it's actually handy because you
意识到它实际上很方便 因为你
don't have to spend all this time like
不用把所有的时间花在
navigating your cursor to something just
将光标导航到某个
so that you can move it your cursor
这样你就可以把它移动到你的光标
could be over here and then just tap it
可能在这里 然后轻敲它
and you're moving it so whilst you're in
当你在里面的时候 你正在移动它
this move state if you want to cancel a
如果您想要取消
movement you can do it one of two ways
你可以用两种方法之一来做运动
you could just hit Escape or you could
你可以直接按Escape键或者你可以
rightclick then if you want to confirm a
如果您想要确认
movement like say I want to move my lamp
像说我想移动我的灯这样的动作
here and I like the movement I could
在这里 我喜欢我能做的运动
just do a single left click so again if
只需单击一次左键 这样如果
I want to cancel something just right
我想取消一些恰到好处的事情
click if I want to confirm the movement
如果我要确认移动 请单击
left click but let's say I wanted to
点击鼠标左键 但假设我想
move it along an axis like you know I
沿着轴移动 就像你知道的那样
like these arrows here and I want to be
就像这些箭头一样 我想成为
able to move it on just a specific axis
能够仅在特定的轴上移动它
well I can do that whilst I'm in that
好的 我可以在我在的时候这么做
grab State as well so after I have hit
在我击球后 也会抓住状态
the g key to grab it I can then tap the
按G键抓住它 然后就可以点击
letter of the axes that I want to move
我要移动的轴的字母
it on so if you don't know in the real
所以如果你不知道在现实中
world and in the 3D software there are
世界上的3D软件中有
three axis cuz there's three dimensions
三轴 因为有三个维度
there's the x axis which I can move it
这是x轴 我可以移动它
by hitting the X key the y axis to move
按下X键即可移动y轴
it back and forth along the Y AIS with
它沿着YAIS来回穿梭
the y key or the Zed axis to move it up
按y键或Zed轴向上移动
and down on the Zed axis so you can
在ZED轴上向下 这样你就可以
remember those uh those letters the X Y
还记得那些呃那些字母X Y吗？
and Zed or the method that I actually
Zed或者我实际使用的方法
prefer to use is whilst you're in that g
更喜欢使用的是当你在那个地方的时候
state if you just hold down the middle
如果你只是按住中间的话
Mouse button and then pull out you can
鼠标按键 然后拉出就可以了
see you get this like Gray Line that
你看你得到的就像灰线一样
pulls out from the center and then if
从中心抽出 然后如果
you just drag out and move around it
你只需拖出并绕过它
will snap it to the nearest axis which
会将其捕捉到最近的轴
again is maybe an odd way to work but
再次工作可能是一种奇怪的方式 但
it's actually really handy because it
它实际上非常方便 因为它
means you don't have to think of the the
意味着你不必考虑
letter and locate it on your keyboard I
字母并在你的键盘上找到它
can just tap G to move it and then
只需轻触G即可移动它 然后
middle Mouse drag out and then just find
鼠标中键拖出 然后找到
that exact axis that I'm looking for and
我正在寻找的那个轴
so it's very fast to just quickly move
所以快速移动是非常快的
the lamp exactly where I want it by the
这盏灯正好在我想要的地方
way if you're finding it hard to
如果你觉得很难
remember all of the keyboard shortcuts
记住所有的键盘快捷键
that I've mentioned I've actually put
我已经提到过 我实际上已经把
together a PDF a cheat sheet of
一份PDF文件和一份
blender's most common hotkeys and you
搅拌机最常用的热键和你
can download that by clicking the link
可以通过点击链接下载
in the description so you could print it
这样你就可以打印它了
out or you could just have it on a
或者你可以把它放在一个
separate monitor while you work also if
在您工作的同时还在以下情况下单独监控
you are from another 3D software package
您来自另一个3D软件包
you might notice that blenders hotkeys
你可能注意到搅拌机的热键
are different than what you are used to
与你所习惯的不同
so if you actually go to preferences
所以如果你真的转到首选项
just for those people that are from
只为那些来自
other softwares if you change the key
如果您更改密钥 则会安装其他软件
map to Industry compatible you'll find
您将找到与行业兼容的地图
that these shortcuts are probably more
这些捷径可能比
in line with what you remember from
与你记忆中的东西一致
other software
其他软件
I'll also put a link to a cheat sheet
我还会放一个链接到一张小抄
that is just for the industry compatible
这只是为了与行业兼容
keymaps that somebody else put together
其他人放在一起的键映射
I've got nothing to do with it but I'll
我和这件事无关 但我会
put that link there so you can check it
把那个链接放在那里 这样你就可以检查它了
out as well for the rest of this
在接下来的时间里也是如此
tutorial series I'm going to use
我将使用的系列教程
blender's hotkeys just keep that in mind
搅拌机的热键只需记住这一点
now let's say as I am moving around here
现在让我们假设当我在这里走动
I'm like oh this looks really good I've
我就像 哦 这看起来真的很好 我已经
got some nice REM lighting across the
得到了一些很好的REM照明
monkeyy face I want to take a photo I
猴子的脸 我想拍张照片
want to take a nice pretty image of this
想要拍一张漂亮的照片吗
and post it on socials for clout right
并把它发布在社交网站上 以求影响力
well I could take a screenshot shot of
好的 我可以截图
it but that would be silly cuz it's got
但那将是愚蠢的 因为它有
all these lines all over it's all noisy
所有这些线路都很嘈杂
right we don't like it the way you take
是的 我们不喜欢你采取的方式
a photo a pretty image in letter is to
一张照片一封漂亮的信中的形象是
do a render so you could do that one or
做一个渲染 这样你就可以做那个 或者
two ways by going up to render and
两种方法 分别是向上渲染和
hitting render image or remembering the
点击渲染图像或记住
hot key which says next to it
旁边写着热键
F12 so when you do that a little window
所以当你这样做的时候 有一个小窗口
will pop up it will use your CPU or GPU
将弹出它将使用您的CPU或GPU
depending on which renderer you've got
取决于您使用的是哪种渲染器
active and it will render out a pretty
活动的 它将呈现一个漂亮的
image and from here you could go image
图像 从这里你可以看到图像
and then save as and that'll save it as
然后另存为 这会将其另存为
PNG or whatever wherever you want to
PNG或任何你想去的地方
save it but you might notice looking at
保存它 但您可能会注意到
this that this is actually a different
这个 这实际上是一个不同的
view than what we have here right so
比我们这里有更多的景观 所以
here I've got a nice view of the
在这里 我有一个很好的视野
monkey's face but up there was a
猴子的脸 但上面有一个
different View and the reason for that
不同的观点及其原因
is when you do a render it's not
当你做渲染的时候 它不是
rendering from The View that you're
从您所在的视图进行渲染
looking at currently it's always going
从目前来看 它总是在进行
to render from the point of view of the
从视图的角度呈现
camera so this is our camera over here
摄像机这是我们的摄像机在这里
and it's looking from this angle and we
从这个角度看 我们
can actually look through the camera by
可以通过摄像机进行实际观察
just clicking the little camera icon
只需点击相机的小图标
there or by remembering the hotkey which
在那里或通过记住热键
is number pad Z
是数字键盘Z
zero so how do we move the camera well
所以我们怎么才能把相机移好呢？
blender is a little awkward maybe a
搅拌机有点笨拙 也许是
little different to other software
与其他软件略有不同
packages but you're supposed to like hit
包裹 但你应该喜欢Hit
G to move it and then like middle Mouse
G移动它 然后点击鼠标中键
to zoom in and out and then if you want
放大和缩小 然后如果你想
to like move it along an axis I guess g
为了让它沿着一个轴移动 我猜是g
and then X you could do that but
然后 你可以这样做 但是
actually what a lot of users prefer
其实很多用户更喜欢的是
especially those from other software
尤其是来自其他软件的软件
packages is if you've got your camera
包裹就是如果你有相机的话
selected which by the way I haven't
顺便说一句 我还没选好
mentioned this but up here this is your
提到了这一点 但在这里这是你的
outliner it's kind of an inventory of
大纲 这是一种库存
every item that you've got in your scene
你的场景中的每一件物品
okay so with the camera there selected
好的 所以选择了那里的摄像头
if I hit n n is to bring up the
如果我按下n n就是调出
properties n for properties for whatever
属性n表示任何对象的属性
reason um and then go to view there's a
推理 嗯 然后去看有一个
little box there that just says lock to
那里有一个小盒子 上面只写着锁到
camera to view so now with that active
处于活动状态的摄像机现在可以查看
if I just use the same keyboard
如果我只用同样的键盘
shortcuts as before middle Mouse button
快捷键与以前一样 鼠标中键
to orbit around shift middle Mouse to
围绕Shift鼠标中键动态观察
drag it you can see that the camera is
拖动它 您可以看到摄像机在
moving with it so essentially the view I
随着它的发展 从本质上讲 观点是
can set it up exactly as I want then hit
可以完全按照我想要的方式设置 然后点击
n again and then I can disable that and
N然后我可以禁用它 然后
then now as I pull out you can see the
现在 当我拔出时 你可以看到
camera will stay exactly where it was
摄像机将原地不动
and I could do a lovely pretty render
我可以做一个可爱的漂亮的渲染
but this is too simple if we post this
但如果我们张贴这篇文章就太简单了
on the internet people are bound to make
在互联网上 人们一定会做出
fun of us imagine that well we could
有趣的是 想象一下 我们可以
give it some color right so with our
给它一些合适的颜色 所以用我们的
monkey head selected we can go over to
猴头精选我们可以去
here to the properties so this
从这里到酒店 所以这个
properties section is where you might
“属性”部分是您可以
spend the other I don't know another
花掉另一个我不知道另一个
eight five to 8% I don't know getting
85%到8% 我不知道
too exact there you might spend another
太精确了 你可能会再花一次
5% of your time in this section but it's
你5%的时间在这一部分 但它是
where all of the properties for things
在那里所有的东西的属性
are in blender so for example you've got
都在搅拌机里 比如你有
uh like the render properties like the
例如呈现属性 如
size of the image that you're saving
要保存的图像的大小
something as is defined there and some
在那里定义的一些东西和一些
of these properties will stay here um no
这些房产中有多少会留在这里 嗯 不
matter what is selected but others are
重要的是选择了什么 但其他人是
selection dependent so you can see
依赖于选择 因此您可以看到
actually if I click the camera there you
事实上 如果我点击那里的摄像头 你
can see I get a little camera tab at the
可以看到我得到了一个小相机标签
bottom there but if I select my monkey
在下面 但如果我选择我的猴子
you'll see the camera tab disappears but
您将看到摄像机选项卡消失 但
instead I have some other ones that
相反 我有一些其他的
appear so one that we might want to
看起来是这样的 我们可能想要
change is underneath material and this
变化是在材料下面 而这
will enable us to add a
将使我们能够添加一个
material change the color to something
材质将颜色更改为某种颜色
else essentially so underneath here
否则本质上就是在这里下面
where it's got new I'm just going to hit
哪里有新的 我就去打
new and then you've got a bunch of
新的 然后你就会有一堆
options very conf o i subsurface again
选项再次浮出水面
don't worry about it we'll get to all of
别担心 我们会到达所有的
that later on the one that defines the
后来 定义了
color is is the base color so if I do a
颜色是基色 所以如果我做一个
single left click on that white box
在白色框上单击鼠标左键
there I can then change this color to
在那里 我可以将此颜色更改为
whatever I want I could uh make it an
无论我想要什么 我都可以让它成为
odd creepy skin toned monkey head right
奇怪的毛骨悚然的皮肤 猴子的头 对
like that and do a random okay so hey
就像这样 做一个随机的 好的 所以嘿
all right it's better but still it's too
好吧 好多了 但还是太
simple I think people will think we
很简单 我想人们会认为我们
haven't put enough effort into this uh
还没有花足够的力气在这上面呢
Masterpiece so let's add another object
杰作 所以让我们添加另一个对象
let's give the monkey a hack so if we
让我们给猴子一次黑客攻击吧 如果我们
want to add another object how do we do
想要添加另一个对象怎么办？
it well we could go to the add menu like
我们可以转到添加菜单 如下所示
I mentioned before or the hotkey shift
我之前提到过或者是热键移位
a so what sort of hat do we want to add
A那么我们想加什么样的帽子呢？
we could do a boxy hat uh let's do a
我们可以做一顶四四方方的帽子 呃 让我们做一个
party hat with a cone so once we've
带圆锥体的派对帽 所以一旦我们
added that object you can see it's just
添加了那个对象 您可以看到它只是
plopped it straight in the center
正中了它的中心
intersecting our monkey so we need to
让我们的猴子相交所以我们需要
move it can move it and we could grab it
移动它可以移动它 我们可以抓住它
with the G key so it's now moving it
用G键 所以它现在在移动它
just on our cursor there I don't want to
就在我们的光标上 我不想
move it just freehand though cuz I like
只是徒手移动 因为我喜欢
the position but I just want to move it
这个职位 但我只想换个位置
up so I'm going to hit Zed to move it
向上 我要击打Zed来移动它
along the Zed axis right I like it there
沿着ZED轴 我喜欢那里
so once I like the placement I'm just
所以一旦我喜欢这个位置 我就会
going to do a single left click okay
我要做一次左键点击 确定
great but too big oh so see need to
太好了 但太大了 所以我需要
learn another tool which is scale so we
学习另一种工具 即扩展 因此我们
could go to the scale tool there and
可以转到那里的缩放工具
then we get this familiar um little axes
然后我们得到这个熟悉的 嗯 小斧头
there but again most people prefer to
但同样 大多数人更愿意
remember the hotkey which for scale is
请记住用于缩放的热键是
just s so s to scale so resizing that
只是S 所以S把规模调整得如此之大
okay that's pretty good let's move it
好的 很好 我们走吧
down again so G and Zed okay all right
再倒一次 G和Zed都还好
but yeah let's say we want to make it a
但是 是的 比方说我们想让它成为
little taller okay so we could scale it
好的 再高一点 这样我们就可以爬上去了
along just the Z axis so s and then Zed
沿着Z轴 S 然后是泽德
whoops s z there we go and it's now
哦 S 我们走了 现在是时候了
making it a tall party hat scale it down
让它成为一顶高高的派对帽子 把它缩小
there we go ha look at that be a very
我们走吧 哈哈 看那是一个非常
Bland party if it's gray though so let's
如果天气是灰色的 那就开个平淡无奇的派对吧
give it another material an exciting
给它另一种令人兴奋的材料
color a vibrant uh
色彩鲜艳 嗯
aqua color why not give that a render by
水色为什么不按如下方式进行渲染
hitting F12 okay camera is in the wrong
按F12即可 相机错误
position so let's go to camera view mode
定位 让我们转到摄像机查看模式
with number pad zero I'm going to select
使用数字键盘零 我将选择
my camera and rather than dabbling with
我的相机 而不是涉足
that little thing I had before I'm going
我临走前的那件小事
to hit G and then middle Mouse just tap
点击G 然后点击鼠标中键即可
it once as I said it's a little awkward
就像我说的 有一次有点尴尬
blend is um the way it handles with the
Blend是它处理
camera but anyway just uh move that out
相机 但不管怎样 呃 把它搬出去
and then uh I got to rotate it done all
然后 呃 我要把它全部旋转起来
right so I'm going to rotate so with the
好的 所以我要旋转 所以随着
camera selected tap r then middle Mouse
选择相机 点击鼠标右键 然后使用鼠标中键
and it's now kind of like free hand
现在它就像是自由的手
rotating around so I'll just uh move it
转来转去 这样我就 呃 移动它
up slightly there we go okay this is
稍微往上一点 我们走 好的 这是
this is just a full around session so
这只是一次完整的会议 所以
don't worry if you're making mistakes
如果你犯了错误 不要担心
we'll get to actual practical building
我们将进入实际的实际建筑
stuff in the next part I'm just trying
下一部分的内容我只是试着
to find ways to throw in these like
想办法把这些东西都扔进去
fundamental tools rotate right the
基本工具向右旋转
monkey's head is just he needs to look
猴子的头只是他需要看一看
dead on at the camera and currently he's
正对着摄像机 目前他正在
off ah what an excuse to use the rotate
离开啊 用轮换是什么借口？
tool so you could enable the rotate tool
工具 以便您可以启用旋转工具
right The Familiar axes there you could
在熟悉的轴线上 你可以
click and rotate it around like that
点击并像这样旋转它
again most people prefer to remember the
再说一次 大多数人更愿意记住
hotkey which is R to rotate right so
按R键向右旋转的热键
it's now just freehand rotating on my
它现在只是徒手旋转在我的
cursor remember the uh the axis as I
光标记住 呃 轴是我的
mentioned before can be used for any
前面提到的可以用于任何
mode so uh the x axis will rotate it
模式 所以 呃 x轴会旋转它
back and forth the Y AIS tilt it or Zed
Y AIS来回倾斜或ZED
there we go to turn it towards the
在那里 我们要把它转向
camera just a little bit right and there
相机就在那里和右边
you go F12 and we've done it let's save
你按F12键 我们做到了 让我们省钱吧
it let's upload it to Art station and
我们把它上传到艺术站 然后
then just wait for the recruiters
那就等招聘人员来吧
essentially all right let's start a new
基本上好吧让我们开始新的
scene so that we can get ready for part
场景以便我们可以为部分做好准备
two where we're going to actually start
我们将真正开始的两个地方
building our donut and learning some of
制作我们的甜甜圈并学习一些
the more core features of blender so
搅拌机的更多核心功能
click here and I will see you in part
点击此处 我将部分见到您
two
两